## Ronny Haase

✓ ronhaase@gmail.com 
✓ ronnyhaase.com 
✓ @ronnyhaase 
✓ /ronnyhaase

♥ Liverpooler Strasse 213349 BerlinGermany

 $\square$  (on request)  $\square$  (on request)

Hi! I'm Ronny, 30 years old and currently based in Berlin.

I'm developing web based solutions for over 10 years with focus on Frontend Development for ~4 years.

Beside excellent knowledge in JavaScript, HTML 5 and CSS 3, as well as testing, optimizing, and debugging for Browsers and JavaScript Engines, I love deliberating about good Design, coding in NodeJS, and thinking about scalable Web applications and services.

## **Key Skills**

JavaScript CoffeeScript CSS 3 HTML 5 jQuery Responsive Web Design / RWD			
Document Object Model (DOM) Unit Tests PhoneGap / Cordova LESS CSS MVC / MV*			
AngularJS BackboneJS EmberJS JSON HTTP REST/RESTful APIs AJAX XHTML			
XML User Interfaces User Experience			
NodeJS Git DevOps Cloud Computing Unix / Linux PHP Ruby SOAP			
Web Services NoSQL CouchDB MongoDB PostgreSQL MySQL			

## **Work Experience**

07/2013 – present United Online, Inc. - StayFriends GmbH Berlin, Germany

Frontend Developer

07/2013 – 11/2013 Freelancer Germany

Frontend Developer // Web Application Developer & -Architekt

- JavaScript-Development for mobile hybrid app "Xanten-App" (see Sample works)
- Design & Implementation of a responsive solution for weeze.de

07/2013 - 09/2013 Parental leave

07/2012 - 06/2013	the a-team GmbH	Berlin, Germany	
	Frontend Developer		
•	Lead Frontend Development for flagship product "iCMP", it's modernization and		
	redevelopment including a in-house JavaScript framework		
•	Frontend Development of websites, software solutions and iCMP modules.		
•	Development of jQuery Plugins		
09/2011 - 06/2012	Freelancer	Germany	
	Frontend Developer // Web Application Developer & -Architect		
•	Among others, Frontend Develop	ers, Frontend Development of "PPM" for Dirk Rossmann GmbH (see Sample	
	works)		
08/2004 - 08/2011	Freelancer (as a side job)	Berlin, Germany	
	Web Developer & -Designer		
01/2004 - 06/2004	BBJ Servis gGmbH	Berlin, Germany	
	Software- & Database-Develope	ſ	
09/2000 - 08/2003	Devcon Software GmbH	Berlin, Germany	
	Trainee as "IT Specialist, Application Development"		
Publications			
11/2011	"PopcornJS – Das HTML5-Media-Framework" Webstandards magazine issue 12/2011 - 2 pages		
P.1			
Education			
10.2009 - 09.2011	Humboldt University of Berlin	Berlin, Germany	
	Study of Computer Science		
08.2004 - 06.2008	Treptow-Kolleg	Berlin, Germany	
	A-Level / Abitur		
09.2000 - 08.2003	Devcon Software GmbH	Berlin, Germany	
	Trainee as "IT Specialist, Application Development"		
Others			
09/2008 - 05/2009	Civilian service at Helene-Häusler-Schule, special school		

## Interests & Skills

Languages German Native language

Englisch Fluent

Hobbies & Interests Music, Photography, Design, Technology, Social Media

Berlin, 01.04.2014